### John Mark Caluya Fuentes

Unit 206/589 Elizabeth Street, Melbourne, VIC 3000

Email: jmcaluyafuentes@gmail.com

Mobile number: 0481744143

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

Dedicated, methodical and highly organised worker. My skills gained from eight years of experience in electronics manufacturing in the Philippines are transferrable to the production operator role. Successful in solving problems and implemented actions to improve product quality, production yield and cost. Trained in ISO 9001 such as health and safety in workplace and continual improvement. Works well with colleagues and pitch in ideas to help achieve team goals.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Analyse product, process and parameters and drive actions for quality, yield and cost improvements
- Evaluation of new product and process conditions from prototyping to mass production
- Experimentation, reliability tests, data analysis and technical documentation
- Process mapping and checking to ensure production areas meet health and safety requirements;
   and to ensure product and processes meet quality standards
- Root cause analysis and investigation of 5M's + 1E factors
- Formulates and implements corrective and preventive actions
- Review and revision of Control Plan, FMEA (Failure Mode and Effect Analysis), Manufacturing and Working Standards

#### **PERSONAL SKILLS**

- · Strong analytical and problem-solving skills
- Methodical, accurate and excellent attention to details
- Good communication and interpersonal skills
- Team player and enjoy working collaboratively with cross-functional team
- Ability to manage various tasks in a fast-paced manufacturing environment
- Solid working knowledge of MS Suite such as Word, Excel, PowerPoint and Outlook
- Highly organized in workplace and diligently applies 5S methodology

#### **WORK HISTORY**

## Spotless Integrated Facilities Services

Auckland, New Zealand May 2022 - Mar 2023 (Casual from Oct 2022)

#### **Area Cleaning Supervisor**

- Supervise cleaners in different sites
- Manage annual/sick leaves and arrange for covers
- Perform cleaning if no cleaners are available
- Safety and risk management of working procedures
- Inspection of cleaning tools and equipment
- Stocks inventory, purchasing and track delivery
- Monthly QA cleaning audit with clients
- Address client's requests and concerns in timely manner

- Analyse and investigate problems and implement actions
- · Review and revise cleaning specifications
- Training of new cleaners
- Provide regular updates to the manager
- Received a recognition as Own'D winner (Jul 2022)

#### **North Shore Hospital**

Auckland, New Zealand Dec 2018 - Mar 2023 (Casual from May 2022)

#### Orderly

- Assist patients, nurses and other medical staff
- Safe and timely transport of patients
- Delivery of specimen samples, documents, various equipment, etc.
- Facilitates waste management in all departments and wards
- Cleaning of several equipment
- Occasionally covers night lead role
- Assigned as blue stream orderly (special role for Covid-19 patients)
- Received CEO's certificate of outstanding work (Dec 2019)
- Completed NZQA Level 3 (2019)
- Trained in proper moving and handling of patients; and basic CPR

Oct 2018 - Work visa was approved. Seasonal worker in kiwifruit orchard for 6 weeks (23 Oct - 7 Dec) Mar 2018 - Arrived in New Zealand on a visitor visa under partnership with my wife

#### Taiyo Yuden (Philippines), Inc.

Cebu, Philippines
Jul 2010 - Feb 2018
(Supervisor from Nov 2014)

#### **Product Engineer**

- Daily monitoring of yield and variance analysis
- Formulation of yield forecast and fiscal year improvement plan
- Root cause analysis and investigation of 5M's +1E factors
- Drive corrective and preventive actions
- Knowledge in SPC and DMAIC
- Process checking to ensure product and parameters meet quality standards
- Experimentation, reliability test and technical documentation
- Cost reduction improvements (lead time down, material change, etc.)
- Review and revision of CP, FMEA, MS and WS
- Assist in ISO 9001, TS/ISO 16949 and customer audits
- Conducts HIRADC and promotes safety in workplace
- Attend/facilitate meetings with cross-functional team
- Provide support to other departments' deliverables in quality assurance, production and delivery
- Correspondence with counterparts in Taiyo Yuden Japan
- Provide education to CFT, operators, inspectors, technicians

#### **QUALIFICATIONS**

# Mindanao University of Science and Technology

Cagayan de Oro City, Philippines Jun 2004 - Apr 2009

# **Bachelor of Science in Electronics and Communications Engineering**

 Board Passer in Electronics Engineers Licensure Examination in the Philippines (Oct 2009)

#### **INTERESTS AND HOBBIES**

Love nature, travel and photography. A softball player. Interested in history.